Hello and welcome to Section 4 now on convolution all neural networks.
We're now going to learn how to build a CNN with tens of float 2.0 and of course the application is
going to be similar to the application we did with our new networks because a convolution on the one
network is mostly used for object recognition face recognition object detection or image classification.
And well speaking of image classification that's exactly what we're going to do in this section because
once again we're going to use a classic and simple datasets so that we can focus on tens of float 2.0
and this classic dataset is the C for 10 data set where this time we don't have to recognize close we
have to recognize objects of Charles airplane a car a bird a cat deer duck frog horse chip truck.
Right.
So we're gonna have lots of images on which are convolution or neural network is going to learn to recognize
them.
And in the end again we'll have an evaluation set where it will measure a relevant accuracy to see which
percentage of correct predictions it manages to achieve.
All right.
So let's do this.
As usual we begin with the step one where we install all the dependencies and notebook chip use setup
as you can notice I did not execute the cell and that's because turns of flow GP 2.0 point 0 is at the
time I'm speaking the version of tensor flow to in Google collab.
But I left the cell in case you know sense of flow evolves and you still want to use tensor flow 2.0
Bono.
Well in that case you would have to execute this cell then after installing all the dependencies we
import the libraries.
And so these are the same libraries as before although I haven't imported them by this time because
we won't use it but I important Matlock late because you're going to see we're going to plot an image
and also I imported the different data set this time which is the CFR 10 data set which is still taken
from the cares modules inside the 10th floor library.
Right.
So the same data sets modules which had also the fashion in this data set and this time we are importing
C4 turn you know just to change and when we call for diversion just to check which version we have well
indeed we have tensor flow 2.0 porno.
All right.
So now let's begin with Step Three data repricing and of course the first step you know any first step
of data pricing is to load the data set.
And again well here that's very simple because thanks to this low data function by the C 410 data set
which is taken from the data sets module by carers Well we import that very very easily.
And again everything is already put into the training set composed of X strain which contains all the
input images and why train which contains the class names for each of the images and the test set composed
of same X containing all the input images of the test and wine test containing all their class names
and speaking of class names well I got them for us here.
Here all the class names that are convolution or neural network will have to recognize and we have indeed
these same objects.
So very different objects actually.
So our new network will have to be trained quite well to recognize them.
This is actually a data set a little bit more challenging than the one we had before.
And you will see that at the end with the accuracy that we managed to achieve and that you will have
to improve yourself.
All right then when we execute this sale will of course this is downloading the data from this Web site
which is the deep Lunar Research Laboratory which contains these datasets that are used mostly for experiments.
You know it once again used as a benchmark you know so that then we can research on some new architectures
of new networks or some brand new deep learning models or even some brand new theory and see if we managed
to beat the leader board for that specific data set and by leader board I mean the highest accuracy
that was able to be achieved on this dataset.
Okay.
And then after we load the data set.
Well we have to normalize the images right.
Remember this.
This is exactly the same.
We want to normalize the images so that our convolution or neural network can train faster and the way
we initialize images is exactly the same as before.
We're going to divide each pixel of all the images by two hundred and fifty five because this is the
highest value that a pixel can have and two hundred and fifty five point zero because we are doing a
float operation and that will put all the pixels in the images into the range 0 and 1.
And that's exactly what normalization is about.
And that will be much better for the training all right and then I actually provided this time the shape
of exchanges so that you can visualize this well.
So this time it's actually in four dimensions as opposed to three as before you know because we only
had black and white images.
And this time we will have colored images.
So that's another reason why it's more challenging this time.
So the first dimension corresponds to simply the indexes of the images.
Right.
So each row of this first dimension corresponds to an image the index of the image.
Then the second and third dimension here corresponds to.
Well you know the two by two dimension of the image.
Meaning you know they're pixels into a 2D array.
Right.
So instead of having 28 by 28 as before we have a size of 32 by 32.
That's the dimensions of the image.
And then we have three here and that corresponds to the RTP format containing the three channels red
green and blue with which you can make colors.
And this will allow our new network to indeed see the colors in the images.
Right so that's Ojibwe scale and of course that's part of the index.
Once again if you're new to this especially deep learning or mostly convolution on the one network well
you have to see the annexes first.
This is a practical course on tensor flow.
We of course provided the theory of deep learning and neural networks and convolution on the one that
works in this course.
In case you're new to this.
And so if that's the case well you have to go see the annexes first.
And we explained that format you know with the three dimensions first two corresponding to the pixels
in the two the arrays.
And the third dimension corresponding to the colors.
All right then once again we divide all the pixels in accessed by 255 the highest value that a pixel
can have.
So that we put all the pixels of excess between 0 and 1.
And so we normalize well x strain and access and then I just plotted with E.M. show by P LTE which is
my plot lib which we imported actually in the libraries just a single image as an example of the test
set actually.
So I'm actually pulling the 10th image of access and that's this one right.
We recognize a plane which are new network will have to recognize in the future.
OK.
So that's done for the image normalization and then the next step is to build a convolution or neural
network.
And we'll see that in the next material.
We're gonna have many steps.
So just make sure you know all the different steps of how to build a convolution or no network on the
theory side.
So you know we start with the convolution with layers.
Then Max bullying and then flattening and then the fully connected layers.
So just make sure you have a quick refresh on that.
And then well let's build our convolution or neural network on sense of flow 2.0.