Hello everyone and welcome to this biking tutorial.
In this video we are going to start with our data validation project.
We are going to complete this project by utilizing the tensor flow data validation package which is
a part of the technology stack called Tesla flow.
Extended the Tesla flow extended is a built around tons of flow to put any model in production end to
end from data validation to serving it on a server.
The first step for our environment setup is to change it from Python free to Python too.
We are doing this because it has a flow data validation is more suited for Python to to change our environment.
Go to edit and then notebook settings in there.
You will have an option to change your runtime type.
It is currently selected to be Python free.
Just select Python two instead under a hardware accelerator.
You can leave it at none but if you want faster performance change to keep you after your media changes
click on save.
It is going to initialize our environment and it's ready to be used.
Now that we have our environment set up it's time to install a few dependencies that we are going to
need.
The first package is Python snappy.
It is here to accelerate the performance of the tens of data validation package.
It is not necessary by all means but it is a good practice to install it will go for the first free
cell and type exclamation mark to use batch commands and then apt there get installed python dev for
Python development and then Python snappy after death.
Execute a self okay.
Now that we have installed our Python snappy package it's time to install the offload data validation
package.
Position your cursor to the next free cell and type exclamation mark pip install dash queue and then
there's a flow data validation.
Execute the cell that tells upload data validation package is now being installed for us it is going
to take some time to install it.
So I'll skip to the part when it's finished.
Welcome back.
Now we have everything installed of our dependencies for our project.
Don't worry about these two errors.
Everything will work in spite of them.
The last thing we have to do in this video is to import our data set to import the data set into Google
club click on the arrow here and go to files.
Here you will find the upload button.
The data set we will be using in the tens of extended sections tends to flow transform and tens flow
data validation sections is a specific data set for the air pollution of the city of Belgrade.
We will provide a data set for you in the resources of both sections so click on upload button and select
the provided CSC which you previously downloaded and one selected click on open.
This is just a reminder for you.
Nothing to worry about so click Okay.
Now we have the data set uploaded to our environment that's everything we have to do for this video
in the next one.
We will continue with our data validation project.
If you have any questions or comments so far please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I'll assume the next tutorial.