Hello, colleagues, in this lesson, we are going to discuss what remote repositories are and how to
work with them.
I will tell you what is the source code hosting and why do we need it together?
We'll review the most popular in services and we'll compare them.
And this will create a remote repository.
I'm going to show you how to push a local repository to the remote.
You run such command as get push today.
I will show you what is with me dot and defile and when you can use it.
And at the end of the lesson, I will show you how you can clone an existing repository for your computer.
Let's start before we start looking at examples.
Let's understand first.
Why do we need remote repositories?
Usually where we work as a team with other software engineers and we need to collaborate with them somehow
and we want to have a single place with our latest version of the code.
Remote repository will help us with this remote repository is the same repository that we already created
in this course, but it's just hosted on the Internet and available online 24/7.
And every developer updates is a remote repository on the regular basis.
Collaborating with remote repositories means that you know how to push changes, how to pull changes
from there and how to resolve conflicts in the source code in case you have any.
Also, we need to know how to set a remote repository beside that, and this course will learn how to
manage various remote branches.
Each developer still has a repository on the local machine, but there is one single place where the
code of the latest version should be placed to start with.
Let's hold a brief overview of what Hosten for remote repositories you can use today.
On this slide, you can see three of the most popular Hosten forget repositories.
They are GitHub, probably one of the most popular Hosten in the world.
It supports a lot of features that supports and helped you to create efficient continuous integration
and continuous deployments processes.
Microsoft acquired GitHub repository for huge amount of money.
And you know, if Microsoft buy something that means a lot of product owners, marketers and developers
start proactively developing the product to win the competition with other vendors.
Mid-Market, it is a great tool made and supported by Atlassian.
This tool is mostly liked by developers because of the great integration with other licensed products
like such popular issue tracking system as JIRA.
It is very convenient to use this tool in conjunction with JIRA and Knowledge Base by Atlassian called
Confluence Getler.
One more popular Hosten forget repositories.
And to be honest, it is really hard to compare this one with previous to more or less.
All these three source code repositories have similar features.
Besides storing all of the source code, Goodlove offers similar features for each track and project
management as GitHub.
What we are going to choose for storing source code for all my students.
I use repositories on the GitHub for storing source code of my own projects, mobile and web apps which
we develop inside my company.
We use BitBucket premolars.
This is because the fact that long time ago BitBucket offered possibility to create private repositories
free of charge.
While this was paid feature in the GitHub.
Today you can create is a public or private repository on the GitHub for free too.
And just in one more time, no matter which online positive we are going to choose, configuration will
be the same.
So let's start our demo.
First of all, we have to create account on the GitHub.
The process of account registration is pretty intuitive and easy.
That's why I won't focus on that.
After you logged in, click on Plus sign here.
Select new repository, create name of your repository.
You can choose a name you would like for the demo purposes.
Let me learn it yet we can skip description.
As of now I want to make it public to be able to share it with you team.
You can keep your own repository, private or public, as you wish.
We don't need to let me read me nor get ignore.
We'll add this by ourselves.
Just press big green button, create repository and here you can find hints what to do next.
In case we don't have a local repository.
One case we want to push local repository to this hosting.
What is also worth to mention is that you can establish connection with it via HTTP protocol or S.H.
establish in connection with the SSA protocol requires additional configuration and I will show you
that in the separate lesson to establish connection via https, no additional configuration is a.
What in this lesson, I will show you how to push files to the Hosten with the help of HTTPS protocol,
that's why we need to click here, OK?
What we need to do now, we need to connect our local repository with this remote hosten how to do this.
Here we can see hints.
Let's go back to our get back and our local repository, first of all, to check that your local repository
isn't connected with any remote repository yet enters the next command, gets remote with option B and
we see that our local repository isn't connected with any other remote repository.
OK, then let's perform the next command.
Copy this https eurorail from here.
Press control and.
Now let's type the following year remote at our region and paste link which we copied to paste link
and it bash press mouse right click and select based option.
But what is a region.
Our region is a shorthand name for the remote repository to be more specific.
This word is used instead of the repository URL to make reference and much easier.
Now we need to connect our local branch master with the master branch in the remote repository all the
time during the development.
Are going to have two versions of the one branch that you will try to synchronize.
For example, if you have Master Branch in your repository, you should have a region master branch
in the remote repository to connect local master branch with a remote master branch.
We have to execute the next command, yet push our region was option.
You must option U stands for upstream.
This option automatically sets the upstream US link in our RAPPA to its central one.
After this one will tell you to pull changes.
It will understand that I want to pull changes exactly from this region.
Branch press enter.
It didn't ask me GitHub login and password because I already stored in my credential manager on my computer.
But most likely you will be asked to enter your GitHub login and password follows the hands on the pop
up windows.
Now let's go back to the Web browser to explore our regional repository.
Refresh the page.
Congratulations.
And you see that you have pushed your changes to the remote git repository.
By the way, can you see the repository description?
Usually people use read me dot and file to put their repository description by convention.
Content on this file is displayed on the homepage of the repository.
That's why, in case you want to put some description here, just to just read me file like we did.
Then one more thing that I want to show you today is how you can clone a remote repository, for example,
the first day you journey to a new job and started work on the new project, you can ask your tech lead
where the repository are and you will be provided with the link you have to clone remote repository
to your machine to be able to work on the source code together with the whole team.
How to clone existing repository.
Let me show you example.
Here is a project with a source code for my Java students.
Let me clone it to my local computer so that I could investigate the source code and push changes that
I want to press the green button and select https for the sake of the example.
Corbisiero now on your computer.
Navigate to any place on a file system you wish.
Choose a directory where you would like to store the source code of this project openly bash in that
directory and execute the next command.
Git clone, mouse, right, click paste and press the button.
Now you can check your folder and you will find all files from remote repository cloned here, including
the folder of the repository here you can find doget folder for this project.
Congratulations.
Now, let's recap what we have learned in this lesson.
Today, we learned what hosting for Repositories is one of the most popular gifts Hosten.
After that, we created account on the GitHub.
In this lesson, you saw how to check remote repository if needed.
Now you can connect your remote repository with the local one and push all necessary changes.
Also, you learned how to set up stream for the gift.
Branch will use this knowledge in the next lessons when will create other branches.
Now you know why you may need README file in your repository and what you have to write there.
In this lesson we reviewed to get KLON Command and I believe you understand how you can clone a repository
to your local machine.
That's all for this lesson.
Thanks a lot for your attention and see you in the next lesson.