And know the students today will install with you, get on your computers, I'll show you where you
can download and how you can install it on your computer after installation, I'm going to show you
basic configuration so that you will be ready for the next lesson.
Today, you will understand what repository is also in this lesson.
You will learn what is good bash.
And we let let's start open your web browser and type get download into the search.
Here's the website that we need.
Just in case, I will leave links to the website in attachments to this lesson.
So when you navigate it here, select your operating system and download the archive.
For Apple, the simple instructions how to install gate four windows.
We have download special guides installer.
Let me walk you through it.
Nable left clicks.
I agree with public license.
It is free for commercial use too, so don't worry about using it.
In commercial projects you have to select components that are needed to be installed.
You can keep the false selection.
Just a few words here.
Here is very convenient explorer integration for Windows.
In any place of your file system you can press right.
Click and open.
Get back or get gui get.
Bush is a special application for Microsoft Windows, which provides possibility to use good command
line.
Bush is a popular shell on Linux and Mac OS.
A Shell is a terminal application used to interface with an operating system.
In other words, Get Basche is a convenient way to have Linux like terminals that supports majority
of Linux Shell comments like file creation, copy of the file and lots of other things to interact with.
Git program get go as a separate program that provides user with graphical user interface to create
new repositories, clone repositories at to stage, commit and do other operations in more interactive
and intuitive manner rather than in git command line.
Later in the course we are going to run different apps that will help you to interact with get in more
intuitive way.
Almost all code EDS for different programming languages supports basic buttons that allows you to work
with GIT.
But I strongly believe that each developer should learn how to work with git bash because with the help
of fancy GUI application where often you can't perform all operations that you want to perform because
there is no exactly that button that you need.
And moreover, before you will press different button in desktop, get applications, you have to know
what this button for and the best way to learn it is to work with it was help to get back for a while.
Get large file storage is a pretty cool thing.
This is an extension that reduces the impact of large files in your repository by downloading the relevant
versions of them.
Lezley, that means it will download extremely huge files only when you will need them.
Let's keep this selected and another to checkboxes here is to associate good configuration files.
Was a default text editor and associate as H files to be run with bosz files with extension S.H. Ashwell
scripts that are used in many variations of Unix like operating systems.
I believe now we can click next.
At least now you know what you have selected here.
You have to choose the full text editor.
I have notepad plus plus installed on my computer.
That's why I didn't suggest it.
But you can choose any other text editor.
You're going to need a text editor in some rare cases when you want to use special comments to leave
content message with the help of command line or during the comments manipulation.
Anyway, I will show you how to change the full text editor whenever you want.
So don't worry about this and press next.
Keep this radio button selected.
It tells you that it will adjust your pass variable so that you can use it in your standard Windows
Command prompt use open SSL library and click next.
This configuration asks you whether you want to convert line endings and you probably already know Newline
character is different in Windows and Linux based systems.
Windows often still use carriage return and line in text files to start a your line.
That's what C RLF stands for in Unix based systems.
Mostly used only Lindfield character.
You can change it if you wish, but for the cross platform development, when team members use different
operating systems, the first radio button is recommended.
Click next.
Here, we need to select the.
Emulator for terminal, I recommend Torleif mean w why can you need to choose a default behavior of
gatepost?
What is getable?
Fastforward Mirch and rebate's.
We are going to learn on the next lessons.
This configuration also possible to change after installation.
Leave default here and click next to store your credentials and manage them in an efficient manner.
You can use git credential manager.
I recommend keeping this radio button selected and able filesystem Cashen that should increase performance
of the gate.
You can skip this one and live it unchecked and now just press install button that said.
Now, when you install the gate open file explorer in any place, click mouse, right, click.
You're going to see bushier option, click on it, and here is your kid Bash.
Congratulations.
Now, the first thing we need to do is to target who we are.
Every snapshot of the file system contains information about the author of The Snapshot.
Probably this was done to easily identify who broke system or who created the defect in the application.
But nevertheless, without telling you who you are, you won't be able to commit changes yet allows
you to set configuration on three different levels, system configurations that will be applied to all
users on your computer and all their repositories, global conflicts that will be applied to all the
repositories on your computer for the current user and local conflicts that will be applied only to
the current repository.
What you need to remember is that values on the lower level overrides values of the upper level.
For example, values that are set in local conflicts will override values from system conflicts because
they are more specific TSAs more important, probably.
You're interested what a repository is because we are using such term.
But I didn't explain.
What does it mean?
I get Repository is a get folder inside the project.
The repository contains multiple files with configuration and current project history to track all changes
made to files in project how to create a good repository.
We are going to learn in the next lesson, but now you understand what this term means.
Right now I suggest proceeding with git installation.
To tell you who you are, you need to perform the following commands.
Get config.
Global username and repetoire.
Here I said username.
And one more comment yet, config.
Global user email and repetoire at example, dot com, I recommend you use global FLAC here to set settings
for all repositories.
These conflicts will be applied on a global level.
That is awesome to check the value of the specific property you can use to get config command.
For example, to check username, I need to type next gate config.
User name.
To list all properties with values, I have to type the following gate config list.
And in this lesson, I promised you to show how you can change the default text editor to change it.
You need to type the following.
Get config lomo core editor.
C program files not paid, plus, plus not paid, plus, plus extra.
Instead of this text in quotes, you have to type the pass to your text editor.
Let's recap what we have learned today, today, we learned how to install, yet you also learned the
basic configuration.
Now you know what is good, Barsh and get gooey.
Now you understand how you can check and said get can fix on different levels, system, global and
local.
Also, you learned what a good repository is.
I believe now we can proceed with our next lesson.
Thanks a lot for your attention and see you in the next lesson.