Hello, colleagues, in this lesson, we'll talk how we can ignore files from Geek and how to Ontrack
files if we don't want to get taken snapshots with these files after today's lesson.
Are going to learn what is a technophile and what should be placed there.
Also, I'm going to show you comments that will help us to track files or even the whole directory with
files in it to make sure that we can check, commit history and consult, will learn to then get your
comment and main attributes that it has.
Let's start I will show you get examples on our demo project to Standard Lesson.
I want to ask you a question.
What files you would like to track with get?
Technically, you can track changes in any file, but does it make sense?
Not always in software development.
There is a sense in tracking changes only in the source code and some configuration files.
There is no need to track files that will be generated again during the program.
Compilation like this binaries files in Java.
Also, there is absolutely no sense to store environments specific files like this claspers file because
colleagues of yours may use different development environment and they wouldn't need those files at
all.
Now, when we know this, we understood that in previous lesson we did the mistake.
Don't worry, we did that mistake on purpose so that you could learn additional important comments just
in case.
Imagine that you realized that you don't want to track changes in the binary files in this file because
it is specific only to the special program and have nothing in common with your source code.
What to do now?
We have to tell you to not track changes in that files anymore, starting from today.
How to do that?
I don't want to simply remove file.
That is the easiest way.
I want just to remove this file from the staging area.
But I still want to keep file in my working tree so I could keep using this file to remove files from
GIT, but still to keep them on the local machine, I have to use the get a ram common with cached attribute.
Let's remove this claspers file, type the following and get Basche get around that will Desh cached
dot claspers dot claspers is a file name and you see claspers file is still present in my work entry,
but it is marked as a removed foget.
Let me show you this in good status.
Here you can see that our claspers file is marked as untracked and deleted from the staging area.
Important thing for you to remember in case you will not use cached FLAC, you will remove a file from
your file system to cached means to keep file in your working directory, but remove it from the staging
area to not track it anymore.
Does it make sense now?
Let's discuss what to do in case you accidentally added to the staging area all files from the directory
because removing files from stage one by one could take a lot of your time.
So in case we wanted to remove from the staging area all files from specific directory, we have to
use our FLAC R stands for cursive with this FLAC all files from the specific directory and from internal
directories within that directory will be removed from the staging area.
Let's tibs the following get our ram desh are double desh cached then slash.
Let's check status, awesome class pass fail, and all files from being directory are excluded from
the staging area.
Now I there's a risk that accidentally those files back to the staging area during the next commit to
avoid this.
Let me tell you to ignore these files and directories, to tell you that I want to ignore something,
I have to create a special file without name and with gift ignore extension to create file from the
git bash console type the following touch.
Don't get ignore that requirement in all Linux terminals allows you to create a new file.
Now you can open this file in any text editor or even here in console, for example.
Now you can find it in your file here and you can open it in notepad if you wish.
But I will teach you how to impress your girlfriend or boyfriend.
I will show you how you can use your console to edit text files.
You can do almost everything with the help of console.
You just need to know what to do.
Typing console.
No, not yet.
Ignore.
Nana is the name of the text editor program for Unix like computer systems, which can be used with
the help of command line interface.
Now we can add any text to this file.
We can use Spartan's here, for example, asterisk, dot gloss.
This will tell you to ignore all files with any name, but with class extension.
In our particular case, we want to ignore all files in the folder.
Then let's write, then slash and we want to ignore class file.
So let's step dot pass.
This is enough for us now, let's save this file and regular text editor, you can press control plus
as buttons here.
We need to follow hints that are written down right here to exit.
Now, a text editor, I have to press control and X simultaneously.
It asks me whether I want to save the file.
I click Y button now it asks me to check the file name.
I keep it the same yet ignore and just press enter button.
Awesome.
Now we have get ignored in our repository.
Let's check the status.
We see the difference.
Now you just ignore that directory and files.
It even does not tell me that directory or claspers file is untracked like it told me before.
It just ignores these files.
By the way, you'd has a collection of getting our files for different programming languages.
I will leave this link and attachments to this lesson.
In my opinion, these files are a good starting point for your own good ignore.
But based on what I saw in these files, I can say that for many languages these technologies are not
completely perfect.
Most likely you would need to adjust it in your project.
But as I said before, it is a good starting point now when I'm totally sure that I ignored all files
that I don't need.
I can add all files to the staging area without any fear all the time.
Usually I will use just add comment was not like this.
Get at DOT.
Because I added to the gift, ignore everything, what I wanted to add.
Now let's commit our changes.
Always remember to write a message that makes sense.
In other lesson, I will tell you best practices for writing comit messages so that each your colleague
could understand your comments get conveyed that I am added to get ignored and removed.
Been from Stadion.
Press enter cool, and the last thing I wanted to show you today is how you can check your cammed history.
You might want to investigate it history just to check what happens and where you are in your project
to check this type.
Next comment, get luck, get log prints to your comment, history of the car and get branch.
In this case, this is out of the master branch.
And you see that from the first lesson we already created three chametz here by default get localist.
The comments made in that repository in reverse chronological order, that is the most recent comments
show up first.
As you can see, this comment list each comment with its checksum, the author's name and email that
they'd written and the commit message.
There are numerous options for Gitlow command.
I'm going to show you only the most helpful options which can help you to get necessary information
during the development.
For example, you can limit the amount of comments that you want to check.
In case I care the most about loss to commit, I have to type the following gig log dash to.
I believe you understood that you can change number to change the amount of commands for review and
as a practical attribute is a formatting.
For example, you can type you'd log double dash pretty equals one line and you can see on the checksum
and conveyed message.
There are multiple other attributes that can allow you to print commands following specific pattern
or to print commands that are related to changes in some specific directory or shortcomings in specific
date.
But in my humble opinion, those options are not used in daily basis because probably there is a lot
of sense for you to print its history in specific format, for example.
But from previous lesson, you remember how to use Get Help command to learn more from documentation.
Meanwhile, we'll keep focus on the most powerful and useful commands that will help you in everyday
activities.
It's look like that's all what I wanted to share with you today.
Let's recap what we have learned today.
Today we learned a lot together.
We learned how to tell you to stop track changes in specific files or directories.
Now we know how to tell you to ignore changes in some specific directories.
After today's lesson, you know how to create GUI Technophile that will work for your specific project.
And at the end of the lesson, we learned how to investigate our committee history.
That's all for today.
Thanks a lot for your attention and see you in the next lesson.