Hello everyone and welcome to this very exciting section throughout this section.
We are going to create our own stock market trading agent with reinforcement learning strategies specifically
for that.
We are going to use deep cue network.
Our board will trade actions for us.
It wont make millions of dollars but it will be mostly positive and just to mention this right the way
we don suggest using this algorithm with your own money trading with this algorithm is on your own risk.
So please be very cautious let's start by setting up our environment and installing all dependencies
for the project okay.
As we did before to set up the environment go to edit and notebook settings and here we can choose the
Python runtime and we can specify a hardware accelerator because the training process of the agent won't
be very easy.
We need to switch it to GPO for hardware accelerator.
After doing that click save the next step is to install all dependencies that we are going to need luckily
there are only two libraries that we have to install so in the first free cell we are going to install
tens offload 2.0.
To do that.
Right.
Exclamation mark pip install tens of flow Dash.
GP You equal equal to point zero point zero point alpha zero execute a cell now that we are down with
a tensor flow.
There is a one library left in most cases it is already installed so this will be just for our track
the library is called PANDAS data reader.
This library helps us to retrieve all stock market data directly to our environment.
It is very easy to use so to install it right.
Exclamation mark pip install pandas dash data reader and execute the cell and that's all what we have
to do in this video in the next video we'll start working on the model itself.
If you have any questions or comments so far please post them in the comments section otherwise I'll
see you in the next tutorial.