Hello and welcome to this new section on artificial neural networks.
We're going to learn how to build an artificial new network in terms of flow 2.0.
And that's why I have here in front of me.
A new notebook which was shared with you too so that you can follow it with me.
And in the annual get a series of practical activities to practice your skills on building artificial
new networks with sense of low 2.0.
All right.
And so as you can see well the first cell is the image of the data set.
We're going to work on which is the fashion minced data set.
That's a classic an artificial neural networks.
And not only it is a classic but also it is used as a benchmark you know to test the power of your artificial
neural networks.
You're going to see that at the end of this notebook.
We will end up with a certain accuracy that we managed to obtain after training the artificial neural
network we'll build on this data set.
And so you know you'll be able to compare this accuracy with other accuracies obtained through other
models and other architectures of new networks and you'll see how well you're doing and how much you
can improve.
So let's do this.
But before we start with the first steps let me show you the original data set that is on Kaggle.
That's why here I precisely the image source from Kaggle and the exact link is this one the fashion
in this data set which is a data set composed of of 70000 images of size 28 by 28 of different clothes.
And you actually have 10 different clothes.
The first one is a T-shirt.
The second one is a trouser then a pullover a dress a coat a sandal a shirt sneaker bag and an ankle
boot.
And so you guess the challenge we're going to have to solve in this new section it is going to be of
course to build a new network that can recognize these objects.
So it will have to predict 10 classes which are these ones here.
And of course it will have to predict them correctly and the accuracy will get.
The end is simply the number of correct predictions out of the total number of images in the test set
which is 10000 right because in total we have 70000 images including 60000 images in the training set
and 10000 images in the test.
And of course we'll train our artificial neural network on the training set after which we will evaluate
it on the test set and this accuracy that will get in the end will be of course computed out of the
ten thousand images of the test set.
All right and then if you want to know more well each image is 28 pixels by 28 pixels which is a total
of seven hundred and eighty four pixels.
That's actually an important number because you know since we are now starting with the classic artificial
neural network and not yet a convolution on the one that worked well you know the input of your new
network will be of one dimension.
It's going to be a one day vector and that's why we will actually do a reshape you know we will reshape
the 2D images you know 28 by 28 into a single input vector of seven hundred and eighty four elements.
So that's important to know this number.
But nor is it we'll be reminded in the implementation.
I also remind that this is a practical course on sense of flow 2.0 and not really a theoretical course
where we learn about auditioning all networks.
So this theory an artificial neural networks is not provided in this section.
It is actually provided at the end of this course in the annex part.
For those of you who need a refresh on artificial new networks or even if you're very new to this you
know you can learn them and you should really if that's the case you know you should start with the
annex parts.
And so actually I was just reminding that indeed for an artificial new network well the input layer
is just one vector composed of a certain number of elements.
And in that case it's going to be 784 elements corresponding to the pixels.
All right then you have to know you know an image processing that each pixel is actually a single value
between 0 and 255 therefore you know our training set and test sets will have 785 columns each one corresponding
to each pixel of the images and the rows in the training and test sets will be the images you know each
row will correspond to an image and all the columns of this row will correspond to different pixels
of this image.
Right.
OK.
So I think we got all the information we needed.
And so now let's start let's start building our artificial new network and sense of flow 2.0.
And the first step as usual is to install the dependencies you know if you want to execute the different
cells of this notebook.
Well I included everything from the installation to how you import it and all the rest of course.
So here as we said everything is already executed and I kept the outputs that we can see together.
But if you want to re execute things again and try for example other architectures of new networks.
Well you can directly re execute the cells here but here we already have the outputs.
Let's not do this.
That's once again what you get after installing tensor flow GP you 2.0 porno with this command so exactly
as in the previous section then in step two we simply bought the libraries and the dataset and so the
libraries that we need are known by.
You know that now tend to flow 2.0 works really well with numbers so we import it and we also import
daytime to get some time related info during the training then sense of flow of course and then tons
of flow that carries data sets.
And that's because it contains that fashion this dataset.
Right.
So it's actually from the data sets module of the caris library.
OK.
So that's it for the introduction and now in and next oil will begin the first code section which is
about data processing after which we'll start building our artificial new network.