Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial.
In this section we are going to use tens of flow light library to convert any model to tens of low light
version of it so we can serve it on a mobile device either Android or IRS.
Before we do anything else we need to set up our environment to use drip you instead of you.
So let's do that.
Go to edit then notable settings and instead of none under hardware acceleration choose GIP you and
click save now your environment is set up to use drip you the first and only library that we have to
install is tends to flow version one point thirteen.
You might ask yourself this causes men to be tends to flow too.
Why are we using this version 1 13.
And it is fair and very good question.
To answer that in terms of flow two they didn't make tens of flow light supported.
At the moment it is very new a library and we are going to use that as flow light only to convert our
model but the model itself is written in the same way as we would use it in terms of flow to.
So once this library is upgraded to support has a flow 2.0 you won't need to change anything.
That's pretty much it.
And it is very straightforward and very useful.
Let's install our library type exclamation mark pip install and instead of installing a offload 2.0
right there's a flow that GPO and equal equal to one point thirteen point one execute a cell it is going
to take some time to install this library.
So for me I didn't have it installed before.
And once it's finish we are ready to go in the next video we are going to work on the data set pre processing
and for now if you have any questions or comments please pause them in the comments section otherwise
I'll see in the next tutorial.