Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial.
In this video we are going to import all product dependencies that we are going to use for this project
and perform data set pre processing steps before we define our model.
The first library to import is tends to flow as always.
This is our library of choice for building neural networks.
The NUM by is library to work with matrices and mathematical operations.
And lastly we have to import our dataset because this module of a course is more about how to convert
a train model and deploy it on mobile device.
We are going to use the same model and same data set from the very beginning of this course which is
called fashion and execute a cell.
Now it's time to perform data cell pre processing steps.
The first step as always is to improve the data set.
So let's do that by defining X train y train as the first output and the second one is X test y test
all of that is equal to fashion I must not load the data.
This function is going to track for the data set and if it's not downloaded it is going to download
it from us.
Now that we have our data loaded it's time to perform some pre processing steps as always when we work
with images it is common to normalize them doing this it will accelerate the training process and it
will make much easier for a model to converge every pixel in an image is ranging from zero to two hundred
and fifty five.
We are going to divide all of them by the maximum value of a pixel which is two fifty five.
So let's do that X train is equal to x train divided by 255 dot you can add these dot but you don't
have to let's do the same thing for X test x test is equal to x test divided by 255 dot and before we
jump into reshaping step of the data set pre processing let's explain why we reshape the data set it
up so let's take the shape of X train as you can see it has sixty thousand images where each image is
in Matrix format twenty eight by twenty eight so standard the image in our case we are going to use
fully connected network that only accepts vectors and not matrices as inputs.
So having that architecture in our mind we need to reshape the data set to be in vector format right.
X train is equal to x strained out to reshape and here we have to specify a new shape of our data set
we are going to say minus one which is going to take all sixty thousand images and then write 28 times
twenty eight which is seven hundred eighty four we will do the same thing for X test so right x test
is equal to x test thought reshape minus one comma 28 times 28.
Execute or cell and our X train and x test are successfully reshaped to be sure let's recheck the shape
of X train and as you can see it has sixty thousand images and now they're in vector format of seven
hundred eighty four numbers and that's it for our dataset pre processing stage if you have any questions
or comments please post them in the comments section otherwise I'll see in the next tutorial.