And now the students in this class and we are going to discuss the topic that will be interesting for
developers who work in such integrated development environment as Eclipse, we're going to learn today
how to integrate it with eclipse for development come for besides buttons and widgets that will configure
an eclipse during the lesson.
I will show you how you can use get Bush directly from the eclipse together on real example.
We are going to learn how to execute basic operations from Eclipse.
I make overview of widgets that will allow you to see good history navigate between branches, push
and pull changes from the remote repository.
After this lesson, you will learn how you can resolve conflicts in eclipse interface.
Let's start and turn the topic.
I said just jump into the practice.
Here's my Eclipse workspace.
I created a completely new workspace and reset perspective for you to default to configure it with you
from scratch.
I have Empathies Java Project, which we did together during the learning of the get in the workspace.
How to Impact Projects into Eclipse.
I'm going to show you in the separate lesson.
Do not lose focus from the topic right now.
When I in the Project Eclipse automatically recognised that there is a git repository and you see that
in square brackets, it is even specifying my current branch.
But nevertheless, I will show you how that you get repository to eclipse manually just in case.
First of all, let's add all views here that we need.
Click on Window Show.
You are the one here git folder or use search bar to find it faster.
I would say that you'd stadion and git repositories.
Those are tools that you need.
One hundred percent.
Well, at least in my opinion, I'm holding control button and with a mouse left click select the options
that I need.
Let's also select get lock and it is good that we have learned how to work with Gatins again.
But at least now you already understand what all these views are about.
You already know what is a staging area, what is a good red flag.
You already know what they're getting directed for basis after we selected all use we need.
Let's press open button.
Nice views were opened just to remind you that you can move these views wherever you like them most
here in the clips, for example.
Let me move git repositories widget here at the bottom with other views.
And you can see that my clips recognized each repository in my project automatically.
But just for the future and just in case, I want you to know how to add the existing repository to
their clips, because it might be that the clips will not automatically recognize that you have not
get folder in your project.
And in this case you have to edit manually.
For the sake of example, let me remove the digital repository from this view in the clips mouse right.
Click remove repository from you because I want to remove git repository only from eclipse view and
I don't want to remove the don't get folder from the file system and I don't want to remove the project
and eclipse associated with this git repository.
I want to keep project in my workspace for you.
That's why I press this button.
Awesome.
Now we don't have any repository here.
You can create a new repository if you wish.
That is similar to executing Mutiny's.
Come on.
You might also an existing repository with the help of the eclipse wizard.
And in case you already have git repository in your computer, you can just add it to the workspace.
I believe there is no need to go over each of this option in detail because creating a good repository
is just specifying directory where you want to create don't get older and present.
Great Bottom Clonan Repository is just specifying the past as a repository and your credentials in case
you want a repository with the help of a HTTPS protocol.
But from my experience, this option at an existing local repository is used most of the times by me,
and I don't know why, probably because I don't rely on the eclipse tools to manage Mangat repository.
Usually I fetch all projects with a simple git clone command in the git bash and after that an important
project to the eclipse and an existing local git repository.
Personally, for me, this option is the easiest one, but my job is to share with you all possible
options and let you decide what works the best for you.
That's why let me show you how I usually add existing local repositories to Eclipse.
And now you should specify a folder where your local repository is located and navigate it to the folder
that we created together during the course while learning Gaede and press select folder button here
clip's shows me repositories that it found in this folder.
I checked this checkbox and press that button and here's my repository back again.
Let me expand it.
It is very convenient to switch branches here.
You might find here local and remote branches nable left click on the massive branch will move me to
the master branch eclipse will ask for confirmation.
Just click checkout and you already know how you check out command works.
So I believe you understood what happened behind the scene and you may see a small T care next to the
massive branch name.
Let me switch back to the Kayseri 09 branch.
Right.
Click on the branch would allow you to do the operations that will want to perform in Git Bush.
You may reset branch in different modes, so it makes and hard.
You may replace your branch if needed, merged, delete, rename and perform all other operations that
you may perform in the git bash.
We don't have docs in our repository yet, so it is empty here.
What a task is will be discussed in the separate question here, you may find your main references in
your repository.
You may check out the if you wish in remote.
You may check to what remote repository you are connected right now in Stasch comments, you can explore
the state of your stasch.
And you're working directory, that is technically a project that may collapse everything here, based
on my experience, I mostly use this section to navigate between branches, create new branch if needed,
and remove all branches.
Let's move on this, Sunny, as a positive name means that I have some onstage changes you may find
similar.
Some here in the package explore how to identify what change are we talking about?
Let's check separate tab for that.
Yet, Stadion here, you can manage what is in the staging area right here, commit message and commit
changes if you want.
You also can commit and push to the remote with a single button click here.
From this view, I see that DOT project file is marked as unstaged changes here.
This is configuration of eclipse file that the groups created after we implement the project into it.
Let me update yet.
Ignore the just ignore this file.
I can't find it in your file in the package Explorer review.
But let me open the gate of you for that.
I click window shoe view navigator.
And this view, I can see old files as they are look like in my file system and here's Technophile,
let me add here DOT Project and save the file.
And you must use it instantly, not project file is gone from unstaged changes and to ignore it, you're
going to press this green plus sign to add all files from this section to the stage changes section.
That's right.
Commit message and troops files ignored.
And I can make a comment by clicking here, but probably I would commit and push changes to the remote
repository simultaneously.
To do this, I have to click on it and push button here in the desert.
You should set up stream branch for the current branch.
That is exactly what we did when we specified you option during the push to the remote repository.
Just click all these buttons until you see confirmation that your changes were pushed because the remote
we may check GitHub, but believe me, changes are there in the remote already.
Let me show you a few more things you can press.
Mouse, right.
Click on the project and you'll find a team section.
This section is integration with it in Eclipse.
And you might find here a lot of different options like fetch from upstream push or bold changes and
many others.
Take your time to investigate the section and ask me in case you have any questions to check, commit
history.
You can press show in history here.
You may see cammed hash commit message, author of the Commit and Date of the Snapshot.
And this window, you can check what files were changed in scope of the particular comment.
You may open the file to see the difference before and after the snapshot to understand what exactly
was changed.
This is where we use a full tool during the investigation of the effects when after specific commit
something went wrong.
Also here in the history, you may reset your branch to a specific committee or check out there.
You just click mouse, right.
Click and select exactly what you need.
Now I want to show you a few more configurations that I found extremely helpful.
I want to tell you how you can add a few buttons here on the toolbar.
Click window perspective, customize perspective.
Now go to the action of ability and select it here.
After that, go to the toolbar visibility and make sure that it is selected here.
Click, apply and close, and now here on the top, you have very convenient buttons.
No matter what you want to do, push back from upstream pool, check out the branch, Rebase Mirch,
or he said you can start the separation's simply by clicking the right button in the toolbar.
And even in case you can't find is important that you need or you want to execute some specific command
was a specific option.
You always may open it feedback directly from Eclipse and start working it to open it.
Bushing An Eclipse finds the icon of the console in the toolbar.
Hear this, click on it and select it.
Bush in the dropdown here in the bus should be installed on your computer.
In either case, you won't be able to find it here in the dropdown list.
Now you may click OK Button and terminal is opened.
Important thing to mention here.
Always pay attention to the directory WAGGETT Bush is opened in case you have multiple yet repositories
in the single eclipse workspace that keeps my open you another directory or it may open your home directory
to make sure that eclipse will open the user right directly.
I always press the project first here and only after that I click open terminal icon homes.
This information will help you.
That is practical, deep.
That is really helpful to students in my opinion.
We didn't talk about Rafalski yet.
Nothing special here.
I believe you already learned in the separate lesson what a greater focus here.
You might find the red flag, if you will domus right click.
You can find additional options that might be useful for you.
And the last things that I wanted to share with you today is to show you how you can resolve conflicts
in eclipse, especially for that I prepared a separate branch where I reproduce, merge conflicts,
state how to reproduce and what merge conflict is.
Please feel free to learn in the separate lesson dedicated to the merge conflicts in this lesson output
the stress only on the eclipse tools to integrate with the grid.
Here is a separate branch with so much conflict in it.
I called the branch merge conflict dilemma.
Usually when you have much conflict, eclipse highlights to your files in which you have much conflict
with the red dots like this.
So now it is impossible to mis file with the next conflict when we open the file, which is a good science
where I get separated for different state of the file from different snapshots.
But the groups offer special tool to merge conflicts in files.
Let me show it to you, Mouse.
Right, click on file game merge two here on top.
You are going to see Kummetz hash that have conflict.
Usually you can't edit text in the window on the right, but you can modify text in the window on the
left.
Here you can click this arrow to place everything from the right window to the left window.
When you are going to have more conflicts, there will be different arrows for each specific conflict.
And after you modify the file on the left, you can press control and ask to save the file.
If we would check the same file in the text editor, we are going to find that all signs that it put
here.
I removed grate in the gas station.
You can put a file to the staging area to more conflict.
As a result, when conflict is resolved, you may see a small asterisk on the file.
And after all, conflicts are resolved and there are no more red dots, you can open it.
Brush and continue.
Is a rebasing or cherrypicking something?
What caused the merge conflicts?
I believe we learned a lot today about the clips and get integration.
Now I want you to take your time and as much heat related violence as possible to learn the material
better.
The best thing to learn this is to practice as much as you can.
Meanwhile, let's recap what we have learned today.
The Navy learned how we might interact with it.
With the help of a glimpse, we learned what views the clips we may use to execute to give commands.
Also today, you saw how you can execute basic operations from a collapse besides the collapse configuration.
We also learned how to use it directly from Eclipse today, where even did can commit and push that
snapshot to the remote repository.
And in the end of the lesson, I showed you how you might use magenta in eclipse.
Hope you enjoyed the lesson.
Thanks a lot for your attention and see you in the next lesson.