Hello and welcome to the section on kind of volitional neural networks.
Super excited that you're joining us for this section as well.
And today we're going to cover off the plan of attack how we're going to learn everything in this section
there's so much to learn.
Let's see how we're going to approach this.
All right.
What we will learn in the section first of all we'll talk about what kind of volitional networks actually
are very important to understand the end goal that you're working towards before you actually start
working towards it.
So we'll hear what features will have a look at a few little examples.
We'll compare the human brain to artificial neural networks in terms of image recognition.
So it'll be a fun light toiled to get us started for this whole section.
Then we'll talk about step one diving straight into it can evolution operations.
So this part of the course contains several steps that we need to go through in order to build a convolution
or neural network.
And that's how these tutorials are going to be broken up.
So this was going to be step one the evolution operation will learn everything about feature detectors.
We'll talk about which are also filters we'll talk about future maps and you know how.
What are the different parameters there what they mean and we'll have a look at some visual examples
as well.
Then we'll talk about step one part be there value layer or real you layer which is the rectified linear
unit and we'll talk about why linearity is not good and how we want more non linearity in our network
for image recognition.
Then we'll talk about step two pooling and we'll understand how pooling works will talk specifically
about Max pooling.
And we also mentioned a couple of things about mean pooling or some pooling and other approaches that
you can take to the process of pooling.
Also in this lecture we'll have a really cool example.
So there'll be a very visual interactive tool that we're going to look at.
So make sure to stick around to the end of that lecture because that's going to add a lot of value to
your learning process.
What we're going to discuss at the end there.
Step three flattening.
So here we will.
It's gonna be a quick tutorial on how to proceed from your pooled layers to your flattened layer and
then we're going to talk about full connections.
This is the very meaty tutorial that puts everything together and puts everything into perspective and
actually shows you how everything works at the end of the day and how those final neurons understand
how to classify image.
Very very important material and hopefully that will summarize or kind of put everything together for
you.
And finally we'll have a summary which will summarize everything we've talked about and as an extra
little feature I've included a tutorial on soft Max and cross entropy.
So you don't have to take this material but I thought it'd be a great addition of knowledge because
these are terms that you will come across when dealing with a conventional neural networks.
So maybe maybe take it right away maybe when you come across these terms you can you will always know
you can come back to this course and take this tutorial to understand better what soft Max and cross
entropy are.
And also as always throughout these tutorials there'll be lots of recommended reading for you to further
up skill and get more knowledge.
And on that note I can't wait to see you on the first tutorial.
This is going to be a very fun and exciting section.
And until next time enjoy deep learning.