Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in this section of the course.
We are going to work on transfer learning and fine tuning project in the first video in this section.
We discussed the what transfer learning is and from this with your own words we are going to apply that
knowledge in practice these cute cats and dogs are images from the dataset that we are going to use
in this section the dataset contains only two classes cats and dogs.
At first glance the task may look very simple.
We as humans can quickly tell what a dog is and what the cat is but that is not that obvious for computers.
Both classes have very similar features eyes years for tails and even the environment is very similar
if we were to create the custom architecture for this task.
We wouldn't achieve more than let's say 75 maybe 80 percent and our goal is to pass 95 percent and get
almost state of the art results on this data set by using transfer learning technique alone.
Before we started with the project let's install all dependencies and set up our environment.
The first step as always is to set up our environment to use drip you instead of you to do that.
Go to edit notebook settings and here you can select your python version and hardware accelerator which
is exactly what we need.
Select the Jeep you from the menu and click save.
Now it's time to install all dependencies for the project.
The first one is tensor flow 2.0 in the first free cell.
Right.
Exclamation mark.
Beep.
Install then the flow that should keep you.
Equals equals to two point zero point zero point alpha zero okay.
Tens of low is installed.
There is one more library to install called TDM.
It is most certainly already installed by default but to be more sure lets try to install it.
Right.
Exclamation mark.
Beep install IDM.
And as we discussed it was already installed which is perfect.
The last thing for this video is to download the data set to our Google color environment this command
will be in the resources for this lesson so you don't have to learn by heart.
But let's explain some of these parts to know what's going on here.
The first part is w get this comment will go to a particular server and download the package to our
local computer then we have this.
Then we have this link which is the location where we can find the data set.
And lastly we have this dash O which is the way to specify the output folder where our data is going
to be saved.
I'll just specify these dot slash the file name.
This will save the file to the current directory and for the file name.
I've just copied the name from the link but you can name it whatever you want.
Execute a cell and it is already downloaded.
Let's go to files here.
You will have these cats and dogs zip file which will unpack in the next video if you have any questions
or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I'll see in the next tutorial.