Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in the previous video.
We started with our transfer learning project but installing all project dependencies and downloading
the data sets for dissection in this video we are going to unpack the data set and import all dependencies
for our project.
Let's walk through all dependencies that we are going to need.
The first one is ice.
It is going to help us to work with folders locate files and work with parts since we have our data
set in the Zip format.
We need to extract the data from it somehow.
That's why we need to import the python library called zip file then we have the name pi library.
As always we are going to use it for matrices and math functions a flow 2.0 our library of choice for
neural networks modelling.
Then we have our map Gottlieb which is here to visualize our images for example take the M is here to
visualize any progress in the project.
It is very easy and cool to use.
And lastly we are importing from the tens of low carers that pre processing that image.
I know it's a long path.
These image data generator we will use it to create automatic image pre processing pipeline at the bottom
of this cell.
We have these magic command for map Gottlieb.
It will make sure that all visualizations stay inside a notebook file and after that we are just printing
out the version of tens of flow library.
The first coding task for this video is to unpack the data set let's specify the path to the data set.
So right data set path is equal to quotes and in quotes right.
Since we are in the current directory just dot slash cats and dogs filter out zip and that is our path.
The first task is not now let's use our ZIP file library to unpack this file first let's specify the
object is equal to zip file dot zip file.
In here we have to provide two arguments.
This zip file takes a file path that we have specified before and mode in what a way to open a file
is it for writing reading or is it just for appending something to it.
In this case we want to opening for reading so just specify are right.
File equal to and let us copy the data set back and for the mode set it to r execute the cell and add
two more codes s
now let's extract and roofing from it.
This zip object has a method called extract all it takes a few arguments but the most important for
us is Beth by default.
This argument is not if we don't provide it it will extract everything to the current folder so we can
leave it to none.
But let us specify to this in the quote specified dot slash which means the current directory execute
a cell and now let's close our ZIP object with a method called Close execute the cell and we are ready
to go to the next step.
But before we jump to the next step let's check what we have extracted go to files and as you can see
we have one new folder called Cats Dogs filtered and that is the folder that we got by extracting everything
from our downloaded file.
If we go to that folder you have two sub folders and one python file this trade folder contains all
training images and they're separated in separate folders by class which is just what we want for our
image data generator that we are going to use and we have the same thing or same folder structure for
our validation dataset this adapter is not by one be use at all since we are implementing everything
from scratch to conclude our video.
Let us define all our dataset parts start by creating a data set path new and set it to the current
directory is always and cats and dogs filtered which is the new folder that we got in from this path.
We are going to derive two new paths one for training data and other one for validation right.
Trained they're equal to eyes dart path that drawing this drawing takes two arguments.
The first one is the base directory which is our data set path new and the second argument is some sub
folder for us just specify train for a validation path.
It's almost the same so copy the line for the train there and where we have the keyword train change
to validation and execute a cell with this we are done with our data set pre processing for now if we
have any questions or comments please post them in the comment section otherwise I'll see in the next
tutorial.