Hello, Jim, in this video, we'll discuss how we are going to communicate to make sure the cloning
process is efficient.
We'll review where to ask questions, how to ask questions, and we'll review communication channels
which exist.
So you could reach out to me to start with.
I would like to emphasize the importance of establishing communication during this course, because
one of the main differences between offline and online learning is availability of the kutcha.
When I teach offline, I can just take my students laptop and is to help him to fix, quote, understand
the root cause of the issue and help students understand better what is wrong during online learning.
It doesn't work that way.
So what I would suggest I encourage you to use questions and answers section as much as you can remember
that when you ask questions, you also help other students to understand learning material better in
case there will be interesting questions.
I will even make a video answers to some of those.
But to be able to answer your questions in efficient way, please put as much details to your question
as you can.
For example, here two examples, which describes the same issue as the first one and three.
Could you please help?
When I try to run this code, I have compilation error.
What should I do?
So here are a few questions.
What is this called quote from lecture or from your homework or from examples provided when you see
compilation error, how does the error message look like?
And since I don't have physical access to your laptop, answering your question can take longer than
it was initially expected by you.
Let's review the second example and we want to try to execute this code.
I see compilation error skarner cannot be resolved to a type where I should look at to fix this issue.
From this message, it's clear to me that most likely you forgot to write an impact statement on the
top of your Java file, and it will be easy for me to help you with answer and code example to fix.
So hope you feel the difference.
What are the communications channels you can use?
I'm here to help you to find your first job in software engineering.
We can connect in LinkedIn and I can confirm your skills on your request.
Why you need to use LinkedIn.
Recruiters in I.T. consultancy often use the social network while looking for candidates.
So feel free to add me to your network and we'll stay in touch.
Also, in case you'll have some ideas to run your own startup, do not hesitate to reach out directly
to me and linked in.
My company is always looking for fresh ideas and we can think through how we can build when we in collaboration
Instagram.
I love Instagram.
We can use Instagram for informal communication, will become friends.
Who knows, probably in the future you will implement a new Facebook and I will be able to apply for
a job in your company or we will build something together.
I do love traveling and probably sometime in the future I will be able to meet anyone who are watching
this video in their country.
Or you can visit me if you wish.
Subscribe to me on Instagram.
You can find my nickname here.
Also, important thing to know in case new course will be started or some events are going to happen
like online streams on YouTube or something else.
You will learn this from the post or from the Instagram stories and definitely Facebook.
I don't spend here too much time and I'm replying faster in Instagram.
But in case you don't have Instagram, I'm still thinking how to reach out to me.
You can find me in Facebook to support our community.
We also have Kilogramme Channel and Trigram Channel.
You will find latest updates about promotional deals, about special offers, discounts, job opportunities
and lots more.
Subscribe to our telegram channel now to not miss important updates and news.
That's all what I wanted to share with you guys.
So now I'm sure that we are able to build communication which will help us to build our learning process
even in a more efficient manner.
See you in the next lesson.
Take care.