Hello everyone and welcome to this biking tutorial.
In this with you we are going to start with our dataset pre processing project for our.
This section will be using tens of low transform which is a part of tens of flow extended technology
stack in the previous section we use denser flow data set validation which is also part of the terms
of flow extended technology stack.
By then it was all about checking whether the data is correct or not.
Now we'll focus on data sets pre processing and the final touches on the data before putting it through
our model to started with the project that we are going to install all dependencies that we are going
to need and to set up the environment as you remember in the last section we had to transfer from spider
free to Python two because then the flow extended stack is more supported and better suited for Python
2 and that is the case here as well.
To start with our environments set up.
Let's go to edit and in notebook settings instead of Python free is our runtime choose Python 2 for
hardware accelerator.
You can leave it.
It's not but you can change it to dupe you for faster pre processing and computation after you made
your changes click on Save everything is initialized and the environment is ready to be used.
The next thing that we have to do in this video is to install all dependencies that we are going to
use for our dissection.
There is only one to be installed and that is tensor flow transform go to the first free cell and type
exclamation mark pip install.
There's a flow dash transform execute a cell and it is going to install and that will be it for this
with you.
We have everything up and running and we are ready to proceed to the next step.
If you have any questions or comments so far please posit them in the comment section.
Otherwise I assume the next tutorial.