Hello, Tim, I hope you found this training course useful for you, let me say thank you for all your
time, your questions and your willingness to learn new things with me in this shirt with you.
Let's discuss what are your next steps live feedback for this course.
I would much appreciate if you have time to review and share experience with others.
Let's stay in touch.
Subscribe to me on Instagram and LinkedIn.
Social networks allow us to not feel the distance and get to know each other better.
Also on my Instagram page, I will make important announcements regarding training courses and our community.
You can find links in attachments to this video.
Do not forget to subscribe to Telegram channel of my long online university, where you may find a lot
of promotional offers and educational notes.
Keep learning and constantly adding new lessons to the existing course and adding completely new courses.
Check my public user profile on YouTube me to find new courses.
So stay tuned.
Keep track of my announcements in Telegram, Instagram and LinkedIn.
Right now, in this very moment, I am working on the new lesson for you.
Thanks a lot for motivation that you give to me when I blow the discourse to you.
To me, I said the lowest price possible to make this course affordable for everyone.
Udemy has maximum length limit for free courses.
I can publish free course only two hours long.
That's why even if my courses are not free, they have the lowest price possible.
Here on Udemy, I have only one goal to grade the best and the most complete online courses that are
available for everyone, and I will keep creating new lessons for all my students.
You already bought this course.
That means no extra charges from you is required.
You will get all new lessons completely free of charge.
I want to say one more time.
Thanks a lot for motivation that you gave to me.
The fact that you are watching this video, sharing your experience with your friends, leaving your
views extremely motivates me to create more useful materials for you, for my team and latest updates
on our telegram channel.
Do not miss announcements regarding new lessons and promotional deals.
I will leave link in attachment.
I believe in the nearest future we will be able to create our own startup community with amazing engineers,
investors, managers and amazing projects.
From today, you can consider yourself as part of a software development company we need you together
with.
You will create incredible things and in case you have ideas for startups, please reach out directly
to me and we will build something together.
And I want to say one more time.
Thanks a lot for your attention and see you in the next lesson.