Hello and welcome to the intuition tutorials for the artificial neural networks part of the course.
Super excited to get these things started.
And today we're going to find out how we're going to tackle this section.
So in this section we will learn the following things.
First of all we'll talk about the neurons.
So there'll be a little bit of neuroscience and we'll find out a bit about how the human brain works
and why we're trying to replicate that.
And we'll also see what the main building block of a neural network of the neuron looks like.
Then in the next story we'll talk about the activation function and we'll look at a couple of examples
of activation functions that you could use in your neural networks.
And we'll find out which ones of which one of them is the most commonly used one in neural networks
and in which layers you would rather use which functions.
Then we'll talk about how neural networks work.
So in contrast to what you would expect and what it was probably conveyed in other courses and tutorials
we're not going to go into the learning.
We're actually going to go into the working of the neural networks first because that way by seeing
a neural network in action that will allow us to understand what we're aiming towards what our goal
is.
So here we'll look at an example of a neural network we're going to look at a very simplified a very
simplified hypothetical example of neural network working to predict housing prices for basically real
estate prices and by looking at that example will understand better exactly what we're aiming towards
and what we want to achieve in the end.
And then we will move on to understanding how neural networks learn because that way we'll be more prepared
for what's coming.
Then we'll talk about gradient descent.
This is also part of neural networks learning and we'll understand how that algorithm is better than
just the brute force method that you might be intending or willing to take as a first resort a first
method that comes to mind.
So we'll find out how great what the advantage of gradient descent are and then we'll talk about stochastic
gradient descent.
It's a it's a continuation of the gradient descent tutorial but it's an even better and even stronger
method and we'll find out exactly how it works.
And finally we'll wrap things up by mentioning the important things about back propagation and summarizing
everything in a step by step a set of instructions for running your artificial neural networks.
I hope this all sounds very exciting to you because I am very excited myself and I can't wait to get
started.
I look forward to seeing you on the first tutorial.
And until then enjoy deep learning.