Hello, Jim, today we're going to discuss with you one more important command that may help you to
modify comit history, then we'll talk about cherrypick.
Come on, as usual, we'll discuss when we need to use this command after we'll understand when we need
to use cherrypick.
Command will proceed with our practice exercise to understand how we can use it.
In this lesson, I will share with you my experience of using cherrypick and I will tell you why this
command is not considered as a best practice.
And even despite that, why we may need to use this command some time.
I'm going to teach you how to cherrypick multiple commands at once and how to resolve conflicts during
cherrypicking.
And at the end of the lesson, I will share with you best practices of using cherrypick.
So when we have to use cherrypick, there are different cases when you might want to use cherrypick
command.
Some of them deliver hotfix to the end user as fast as possible.
Imagine that you created Reles Branch.
Rie's branch should contain only source code that is going to be part of the built of your application
that is going to be deployed on your production environment where it will be available to the end user.
And imagine that you realize that you're basing on merging of the latest changes before creation of
the release branch.
You missed important change and now you have a defect in the release branch.
The fix for this defect is present in the snapshot in your feature branch.
It was tested.
It was approved.
So the only thing that you have to do is to move the committee from the feature branch to your branch
and to move one snapshot from one branch to another.
We have to use the feature command or imagine another case and doing changes and restoring lost Kummetz.
Not all branches are merged into the master branch and some chametz might be lost using letterer floor
command.
You may find snapshots that you need and cherrypick it into your branch.
One more scenario, regular time collaboration in case you and team members work on the same feature
and you have some shared functionality, you might want to test something on your branch that includes
other changes.
For example, backend engineers created a data structure that Fronton team also needs to use, and Fronton
developers may use cherrypick command to get those changes into their branch.
Probably during the life of the developer, you will find other real life cases when you may use to
be command, but I believe you understand why you may want to use it.
And now attention.
I don't want you to share with attack tactless information.
That and reporter had told you that using of cherrypick is a best practice.
I want to say that cherrypick command usually consider is not a good practice and regular mergers are
preferred instead when it is possible.
But sometimes you might want to use this command while you Topeka's consider it is not a best practice
notice.
I said literally consider it not as a best practice, but not necessarily the bad thing.
To understand this, let's review how Get-Rich-Quick works.
It creates a tension separate come.
It was different hash and has no reference to original comment.
Content of command will be fully duplicated, but it will consider Newcome it an original one as two
different commands.
That's why some developers may consider cherrypick as a bad thing because it may cause problems like
having duplicate commands and multiple branches messing up with a good history and others.
But in case you are using this command attentively, there is no harm in that.
For example, there might be cases when you can't merge some branch because it contains a lot of other
changes that are not needed anymore.
And at some specific moment of time, you need only one single command.
That's where cherrypick command may help you so used cherrypick with caution.
At the end of the lesson, we are going to summarize rules that you have to follow during the cherrypicking.
Now let me show you the real example of cherrypicking the head for this lesson for the sake of the Dharma
Abbotabad branch was fuken its.
Let me briefly explain to you the state of my current repository so that you would understand the example.
Imagine that I am working on the implementation of LOG-IN functionality and I create a separate branch
for that was the name Keet three zero eight log.
Again, you can see that I am currently on it.
Let me show you the history of what I have already done.
This log was option one line necessary.
Option one line allows me to format output in a bit different ways than usual.
I press enter here what I have already done while being on this branch.
I implement in styles for login bottom.
Also I implement and backend part of login feature.
And here's a snapshot of the original master branch.
And imagine that during the.
Essence of my work quality assurance engineers found a lot of defects, and we are not in the position
to match my branch to a three zero eight into the master branch, but everybody really liked the style
of my login button and product on requested to have the other buttons in the same style.
That's why I want to prepare pool requests for only styles of my button and we'll merge that branch
into the master so that other developers also will be able to pick up the changes.
While I will be fixing all the defects.
Was back in court for the next week or two.
Just joking, you know that I would fix it faster.
But just as an example, this shouldn't be a problem because I will rebase my branch with the back and
quote on the master before merging or even just remove Starlin snapshot from the current branch to understand
the real life case.
Let me now show you how to do that.
First of all, let me create the branch from the latest master branch.
Good switch, master.
Nudes, which resorption CGA three zero nine modern styles.
OK, I'm on the new branch and imagine that I did some changes in the log into this House file, just
did any random changes, Nonno style slash log in order to assess.
Let me write here some text, some changes.
And save it now, let me come in this year to commit with option A and resorption and subcamp.
Hypocenter and now being on this branch, I have to cherry pick this game, it was Jackson E, C, six,
B, five, E, C, two copies that come in and apply it on my new branch.
Let me execute the next command.
Get cherrypick E, C six.
B, five.
E, c.
In case we wouldn't adjust the says as file, we want to see conflicts here and your it would be applied,
but that is way too easy for you.
I wanted to imitate state of the conflict during the cherrypicking to show you the process of the conflict
resolving during the cherrypick.
You see that it indicates that we are in the process of the cherry picking and gives us advice to resolve
conflicts and add files to the staging area.
Let me check your status.
And see here in the but it is said that there is a conflict in Logan says file, so let's open it in
the editor and let's resolve the conflicts now.
No styles log into SS will imitate the fact that we resolved all conflicts.
Now, let's mark this file as a result, get at DOT.
Now, let's continue our cherry picking process to do this, let's perform the next command, get cherrypick
with option continue and it allows us to adjust, commit message by default.
It keeps the region commit message of the previous commit.
Let's save and close this file and we can see that we applied our changes here.
Let's check our current history.
Good luck with option one line.
That's three.
And here's our new comment and attention, in case you would compare, check some of this comet and
check some of original comet from a three zero eight range, you're going to find that they are different.
That means that these two are not the same comet.
This one is just a copy of the first one.
And now a few more important variations and options of cherrypick command in case something went wrong
during the conflict resolution.
You can just abort the process of cherrypicking like this, get cherrypick with option abort.
Also, if you wish, you may cherry pick multiple comets at once.
To do this.
You have specified checksum of all comets separated by space like this year.
Cherrypick E, C six B five e C and three F three one six six six.
Those are two comets from our damos.
Now when you know how to use cherrypick, let's talk about the best practices.
The rule number one, if it's not critical and you can apply necessary changes with much opt for much
option, it is considered to be a general practice to prefer much option of a cherrypick rule number
to avoid creating any duplication by using cherrypick if you cherry picked commands and removed all
branch or just reset the old branch.
That's fine.
And this will not lead to any issues.
Potential issues may happen in case you keep two branches and have duplicated Kummetz.
Rule number three, sometimes it is considered as a good practice during the cherrypick to specify the
hash code or the original commit, it may help you to do this in case you will use exception like this.
Get your pick was option X.
This option will automatically adds information about the regional committee into your new one.
And here on the screenshot, you may see how your comit message will look like.
You learned a lot today about cherrypick, let's recap what we have learned today.
Now, you know when you might need to apply cherrypick command, because we discussed with you different
cases when this command will help you.
Also, you understood why cherrypick is not considered to be as a good practice.
One real example, you saw how to resolve conflicts during cherrypicking.
Now you know how to cherrypick multiple Kummetz at once.
And at the end of the lesson, we learned best practices of using cherrypick command.
That's all for today.
Thanks a lot for your attention and see you in the next lesson.